Grigory Orlov

Senior Frontend Developer

gri-go-riy@outlook.com +7 919 638-1005 linkedin.com/in/grigoriy-orlov

T-shaped, responsible, and collaborative Software Engineer and Team Lead. 8+ years of experience in development in startups, consultancies, and product companies. Advanced skills in frontend development, an expert in JavaScript, various frontend frameworks, and libraries. Comprehensive knowledge of Java and backend utilities. Passionate about user experience and clear software architecture. Fond of sharing and engaging in productive meetings within a team environment.

Technical Skills

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, Golang

Frameworks & libs ReactJS, Svelte, Effector, Recoil, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, TreeJS, OSM, ExpressJS, Spring, WebRTC

Professional Experience

Natera Inc

Senior Frontend Engineer Dec 2019 - present

Developed a flexible platform to allow customers to select a clinic and book medical services online

- Migrated a complex legacy project from JavaScript/AngularJS to TypeScript/React with unit and integrating testing
- Significantly increased accessibility for mobile devices
- Developed and implemented a UI-library with Unit tests and documentation based on Storybook
- Designed frontend architecture
- Led and influenced software engineering best practices within teams for the full software development life cycle, including documentation, design, coding standards, code reviews, building, testing, deployment, etc.
- Led a team of 5 members

Diginavis

Senior Software Engineer Nov 2018 - Dec 2019

Developed a high-loaded management system for unmanned vehicles

- Designed and developed a scalable, real-time ReactJS application
- Improved performance from 10 to 60 FPS for the most loaded parts of the app
- Implemented CI/CD for the frontend part of the application
- Developed and Implemented multi-domain OAuth-based authentication
- Developed and Implemented a JS library for the visualization of on-map data
- Coordinated the teamwork of 3 developers

ITeco

Software Engineer & Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2016 - Nov 2018

Developed and successfully delivered SPA (part of a complex enterprise solution) for letting clients book deposit boxes online for one of the biggest banks in Russia

- Developed and implemented a module for remote printing
- Created around 20 new components for the internal UI library
- Achieved 90+% in test coverage on the Backend side
- Implemented integration with other banking modules and flows
- Made several major CI/CD improvements which allowed to reduce deployment time from 17 to 3 minutes
- Interviewed 30 candidates and mentored 4 junior engineers

Freelance & Web Studios (SEMark, Constanta plus)

Web developer & Lead Web Developer

Sep 2012 - Feb 2016

- Developed various company projects as a full-stack JavaScript/PHP & Python developer
- Led the development of Web and Mobile applications
- · Developed and delivered a solution to allow local governments to handle incoming citizens' applications
- Delivered innovative technical solutions to improve business outcomes
- Implemented integration with third-party APIs

Education

Master of Computer Science

Saratov State Technical University, 2016